Miguel Rodrigues

Matosinhos, Porto, Portugal, 4460-170

🛮 (+351) 910 920 245 | 🗷 josemiguel443@gmail.com | 🛠 joserodrigues443.github.io | 🖸 JoseRodrigues443 | 🛅

josé-rodrigues-165290110 | **У** @JosRodr63795423

"A jack of all trades is a master of none, but oftentimes better than a master of one"



2020 - 2021

Summary_

With more than 6 years of experience as a Software Developer adept at bringing forth architecture design, testing, and maintenance of software systems. Created two teams from scratch (at Farfetch and Axonius) focused on guiding technical initiatives that allowed companies to invest in new areas of expertise.

Work Experience __

Axonius Inc.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER May 2022 - Current

- · Was the first member of the Portuguese tech cluster.
- Focused on growing tech knowledge for the new team.
- · Supported and created multiple adapters that allowed us to show security concerns and connections to the clients.
- Tech Stack: Python, Mongo, AWS.

Farfetch LC.

SENIOR RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

2021 - May. 2022

- The first member of the Research and Development team focused on investing in new tech solutions in areas like:
 - Virtual reality

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Distributed computing (Blockchain and IPFS)
- · Was a node operator of the Diem Consortium Blockchain (formerly called Libra by Facebook/Meta) alongside elements from Spotify, Uber, Shopify, and many.
- Created a POC for virtual reality that allows clients to see 3D digital assets on the phone apps
- Used Nvidia Geforce Now API and Google Stadia
- · Started the Product Verity initiative project
 - Uses tags with random patterns to identify real luxury items. "Is this Gucci jacket really authentic? Let me take a photo of the unique
 - Then provides the real owner a unique digital certificate (an NFT on the blockchain) that identifies and validates the product.
 - The owner that way can resell or present their personal collection on a safe manner on the market
- Tech Stack: Dotnet, Typescript, Solidity (Ethereum blockchain programming language), Rust, Kafka, MSSQL, Cassandra, Docker, ArgoCD, Azure, OpenAPi, and Kubernetes.

Farfetch LC.

• Architectural role in the arch cluster at Farfetch

- Created and managed multiple company-critical projects like:
 - The Globalization project that allows micro-services to handle multi-country requirements (location, time-zones, best delivery paths, and other metrics)
 - The Communication Hub, a highway for internal communications of all the micro-services based on Kafka, used in internal communications and external contact to clients via SMS/Email/Webhooks/Integration's and others
- Beta team for the new deployment system using Elm Chart and ArgoCd
- Tech Stack: Dotnet, Python, Kafka, MSSQL, Cassandra, Docker, Azure, ArgoCD, OpenAPi and Kubernetes.

Critical Manufacturing SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2018 - 2019

- · Core team developer for the manufacturing execution system (MES) that manages complex production pipelines
- The product development team creates and manages the main framework for developing a highly flexible MES that adapts to different clients like:
 - Renault, BMW, IKEA, Braun, Philips, Johnson & Johnson, and many others
- · Worked on the Migration Task Force responsible for migrating the legacy system, for a more robust and modern alternative
- Tech Stack: Dotnet, Angular, Typescript, MSSQL, Docker, Docker Swarm (moved to K8s) and Kubernetes.

E-Goi Matosinhos, Portugal

2017 - 2018 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- · Developed and maintained of the E-Goi Marketing system.
- Provided mechanisms to allow communication using Push notification, SMS, Email, voice marketing, and many others.
- Tech Stack: Laravel, Postgres, Redis, Vue, Linux.

E-Goi

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Created the Sync2E-goi project that: Allows clients to integrate platforms to the E-goi marketing.
- Allowed Costumers to leave competitors like Mailchimp and migrate to the company Uses external systems like Zappier to improve the current E-Goi platform with minimal configuration
- Tech Stack: Laravel, Postgres, Redis, Vue, Linux.

Education

ISEP (Higher Institute of Engineering of Porto)

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2015 - 2018

2016 - 2017

ATEC Training Academy

2015 - 2018

SPECIALIST IN NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS MANAGEMENT

- · Cisco network specialist CCNA 1
- · Cisco network specialist CCNA 2
- Cisco network specialist CCENT

Projects

A Simple Blockchain in Go

JoseRodrigues443/gochain

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

GOCHAIN • A Blockchain that supports both POW (proof of work) and POS (proof of stake) algorithms.

• See at: https://github.com/JoseRodrigues443/gochain

How make your content last forever on the web

JoseRodrigues443/blogger-ipfs

BLOGGER IPFS

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

- · A blog maker that uses the InterPlanetary File System protocol to create blog posts that cannot be lost and will scale to the entire world automatically
- See at: https://github.com/JoseRodrigues443/blogger-ipfs

Have a bot that sends cute things

PUPPY SENDER TELEGRAM

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

- · A blog maker that uses the InterPlanetary File System protocol to create blog posts that cannot be lost and will scale to the entire world automatically
- See at: https://github.com/JoseRodrigues443/puppy-sender-telegram

Blog posts, projects and many more to see

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

• See at: https://joserodrigues443.github.io

Extracurricular Activity

School of Music Oscar Silva)

SEE MORE PROJECTS AT MY BLOG

VIOLIN PLAYER